QualCanvas is a visual workspace for qualitative researchers.
It keeps transcripts, codes, analytical connections and research memos together,
so you can see how an interpretation developed instead of
reconstructing it at the end.
The product is designed for interview studies, field notes, open-text
survey responses and other qualitative material.
The first goal is simple: bring a source into a
workspace without turning your analysis into a spreadsheet.
On the canvas, each source remains readable.
Codes sit beside the passages they describe, and the links
between them make recurring patterns visible across the study.
When you are ready to analyse, the tools are grouped by purpose.
Explore text, inspect coding patterns, compare cases or build a
framework matrix without losing the path back to the source.
The codebook gives the project a shared vocabulary.
Review definitions, counts and hierarchy, then refine the structure as
your interpretation changes.
Export a report for writing, an Excel workbook for review,
an image for a presentation, or QDPX for exchange with
compatible qualitative-analysis tools.
Your work is not trapped in the canvas.
Start with one transcript and one research question.
Build the interpretation in small, reviewable steps, and use the
guide whenever you need the next task.
Visit qualcanvas dot com to begin.