You do not need to configure every feature before starting.
A useful first QualCanvas project needs a clear study name,
one research question and one synthetic or properly approved source
to practise with.
You can begin on the free plan without a card.
Check the current plan limits before importing a large study,
and use an institutional route when governance or team controls
are part of the protocol.
The canvas list is your project home.
Use a specific name that another researcher will recognise, especially
when you expect several phases, samples or analytic approaches.
Create a blank canvas when the structure should emerge from the material.
Use a template when you want a starting codebook or
workflow, then edit it to match the study rather than
treating it as a fixed method.
The left navigator tracks codes and sources.
The centre is the spatial canvas.
Primary actions sit across the top, while the status bar
shows connection, save state, zoom and the command shortcut.
If the interface feels dense, open Help.
Take the product tour, view the keyboard shortcuts or open
the complete guide.
Learn one outcome at a time instead of trying to
memorise every menu.
A successful first session ends with one canvas, one source,
one code and one short memo about what you noticed.
That is enough to understand the core loop and return with confidence.