A transcript is more than a block of text.
Before import, confirm that the study permits this storage location,
remove direct identifiers where appropriate and use synthetic material whenever
you are only learning the interface.
The public guide explains the supported source workflow and current limits.
Review it before a large import so file types, transcript
length and plan limits do not interrupt the study.
In the workspace, open Transcript.
Choose the path that matches your material, give the source
a useful title and keep participant identifiers out of the
title unless the protocol explicitly allows them.
The Sources tab provides a compact inventory.
Use it to confirm that each interview arrived once, spot
naming inconsistencies and return to a particular source without searching
the whole canvas.
Open the transcript node and read around each passage before coding.
Qualitative meaning depends on context, so avoid creating a code
from a highlighted phrase alone when the surrounding answer changes
its interpretation.
For real participant material, align QualCanvas with the consent form,
ethics approval and institutional policy.
The privacy page documents retention, deletion, portability and service-provider locations;
your protocol remains the controlling boundary.
The safe habit is straightforward: check permission, remove unnecessary identifiers,
name the source clearly and verify the import once.
Then you are ready to code.