QualCanvas offers several analysis views, but the tool should follow the question.
Decide whether you need to inspect language, coding patterns, cases
or a developing framework before opening a chart.
The Analyze menu separates text exploration from coding analysis and comparative frameworks.
That structure helps you choose a method instead of clicking
every output and keeping only the one that looks persuasive.
The dashboard is useful for checking coverage, code distribution and project progress.
Uneven counts may reveal a sampling issue, a code that
is too broad or simply a concept that appears less
often.
Co-occurrence shows codes that overlap in passages.
Coding queries let you combine conditions with and, or and not.
Neither establishes causation; both help you find material worth rereading.
Analysis nodes live on the same canvas as the source material.
Position a result near the relevant codes, then write a
memo that records what you think it means and what
could contradict it.
Before reporting a frequency or matrix, inspect the code definitions and examples.
If coders used a label inconsistently, refine or recode before
treating the result as stable.
The strongest analysis loop is question, inspect, reread, memo and challenge.
Use the visual outputs to locate evidence, then make the
argument in your own analytical voice.