A code tells you how a passage was classified.
A research memo records the analytical reasoning around that decision:
what you noticed, what changed and what evidence might challenge
the interpretation.
Open Memo and place it near the relevant source or code.
A useful memo names the emerging idea, records uncertainty and
ends with a next action such as comparing another case
or revisiting a definition.
The canvas lets you arrange reasoning spatially.
Keep a memo close to the evidence it interprets, and
use groups carefully so organisation supports the argument rather than
replacing it.
The Ethics view helps keep governance questions visible.
Record the boundaries that matter to the study, but remember
that software prompts do not replace consent terms, ethics approval
or institutional policy.
The Tools menu gathers supporting views for methods and quality work.
Use excerpts and the codebook to inspect evidence, and generate
a methods statement only after confirming that it accurately describes
what you did.
Exported reports can support supervision, team review or writing.
When AI was used, include the relevant disclosure and retain
the human decisions behind accepted or rejected suggestions.
You do not need to document every click.
Document the decisions that changed the analysis: the reason, the
evidence and any later revision.
That is the trail another researcher can follow.