Collaboration works best when access has a purpose.
Decide whether someone needs to view, code, review or manage
the project before sharing a canvas or inviting them into
a team workflow.
For a team study, agree who owns the codebook, when
coders work independently and how disagreements will be resolved.
Software can show activity; it cannot make those methodological decisions for you.
Open Share from the workspace and use the available access controls.
A share code or link grants access, so send it
through an appropriate channel and revoke or rotate it when
the collaboration ends.
Before checking agreement, confirm that every coder worked from the
same definitions and unit of analysis.
A metric cannot rescue an ambiguous codebook or inconsistent passage boundaries.
The intercoder view can calculate agreement from comparable coding work.
Treat the score as a signal: inspect the disagreements, discuss
the reasoning and revise the codebook when the pattern reveals
genuine ambiguity.
When coders disagree, return to the passage and its context.
Record the resolution in a memo so the next similar
case is handled consistently and the methods account remains transparent.
A sound collaboration has clear roles, shared definitions, a period
of independent work and a documented discussion of differences.
QualCanvas supports that process; the research team remains responsible for it.