QualCanvas AI features run only when you choose an AI action.
They can suggest codes, draft a summary or help sketch
a framework, but they do not watch the project in
the background or make an interpretation final.
The AI use policy explains the request path.
Relevant prompt and source text are sent through the QualCanvas
backend to the selected provider for that request.
QualCanvas records usage metadata, not the prompt or response content.
The AI menu keeps each action explicit.
Select only the material needed for the task, review every
suggestion and keep a non-AI workflow when the consent form
or ethics approval does not cover external model processing.
You can configure a supported provider key in account settings
when your institution prefers direct provider governance.
Keys are encrypted at rest, and the provider relationship still
needs to fit your protocol and data-processing requirements.
Sending an excerpt to a model provider is a data-processing step.
Confirm lawful basis, processor terms and participant disclosure before using
AI with real research data.
An available button is not ethical permission.
Where the study uses AI, document the provider, model, feature
and human decision process.
QualCanvas can export an AI disclosure record, but you should
verify that the final methods statement matches the actual study.
The safe pattern is minimise what you send, review every
result, document the assistance and remain accountable for the interpretation.
Visit qualcanvas dot com slash trust slash AI for the current policy.