An export is a handoff, not just a download.
Decide whether the next person needs to read the argument,
inspect the codebook, reuse the project in another tool or
see the visual structure.
Open Export and choose the format by purpose.
A canvas image is useful for slides.
A report supports reading.
Excel supports tabular review.
QDPX supports exchange with compatible qualitative-analysis software.
Before handing off a codebook, review names, definitions, hierarchy and examples.
A list of labels without decision rules gives the next
coder very little chance of applying them consistently.
For a visual export, fit the relevant nodes into view
and remove unnecessary empty space.
Check the image at ordinary slide or document size; tiny
transcript text is not useful evidence.
The guide documents the current export choices and their intended use.
Review it before a deadline, especially when another application, committee
or archive requires a specific format.
Downloaded files are outside QualCanvas access controls.
Store them in the approved location, limit onward sharing and
apply the study's retention and deletion rules to every copy.
Before exporting, confirm the purpose, choose the right format, test
readability and send the file to an approved destination.
That turns a download into a responsible handoff.