This walkthrough connects the whole QualCanvas workflow.
The exact method belongs to your study, but the practical
sequence is consistent: set up carefully, keep evidence visible and
document the decisions that turn coding into an argument.
Create a canvas with a name that identifies the study and phase.
Begin blank or use a methodology template, then adapt every
starting code or question to the actual protocol.
Add transcripts or other supported sources using clear, non-identifying titles where appropriate.
Verify each import and keep a source inventory before analysis expands.
Read each passage in context, apply a code that answers
the research question and compare new examples with earlier ones.
Refine the codebook when meanings drift or overlap.
Use text, coding or framework tools to locate patterns and exceptions.
Treat every output as a route back to the material,
not as an automatic finding.
Write memos as the interpretation develops.
Link claims to evidence, note alternative explanations and record why
a code, case or theme changed.
For team coding, inspect agreement and disagreements.
For every study, review the codebook, ethics boundaries and analytical
trail before describing the process in a methods section.
Export the report, codebook, workbook, visual or exchange file that
the next step requires.
Verify the result, protect the downloaded copy and keep the
original project available for trace-back.
The value of the workflow is the visible chain from
source to code, pattern, memo and claim.
QualCanvas organises that chain; the researcher remains responsible for its meaning.