In a methods course or research team, the valuable conversation
is why a passage was coded in a particular way.
QualCanvas keeps the excerpt, definition and developing structure visible enough
to discuss together.
The institutions page outlines options for methods teaching, labs and governed deployments.
Confirm procurement, hosting and data-processing requirements before a cohort uploads
any real participant material.
Begin a calibration exercise with explicit definitions and passage boundaries.
Ask learners to code independently before showing the class distribution,
so the result reflects their decisions rather than group influence.
Agreement metrics can identify codes or excerpts that need discussion.
Open the disagreements, ask each coder to explain the reasoning
and revise the codebook only when the discussion supports a
clearer rule.
For teaching, prefer synthetic transcripts or material licensed for classroom use.
Share only with the intended cohort, and remove access when
the exercise ends.
The same structure supports a research team: define roles, schedule
independent coding, review disagreements and document decisions.
Real-time tools make coordination easier, but the team still owns the method.
Whether you are teaching a class or coordinating a lab,
keep the evidence shared, the initial judgement independent and the
review documented.
That builds confidence without pretending qualitative interpretation is mechanical.