If your survey includes open-text answers, QualCanvas can bring them
into the same visual coding workflow as interview material.
Start with a clean CSV exported from your survey system,
and remove fields you do not need for analysis.
Inside a canvas, choose Survey to open the CSV importer.
Select the file only after checking its first row contains
clear column headings and each response occupies a consistent row.
After the file is read, map the column that names
each item, the column containing the open-text response and, when
appropriate, a case field.
Use a research identifier rather than a participant's real name.
Open Sources and spot-check several imported items.
Confirm the response count, make sure headings have not become
content and check that line breaks and characters survived the
CSV export.
Code meaningful excerpts rather than treating every row as a single idea.
The source, selected passage, code and later analytical structure remain
connected, which makes survey interpretations easier to review.
A CSV can quietly contain email addresses, IP fields or
demographic combinations that identify someone.
Remove unnecessary columns, follow your consent and retention rules, and
use the Ethics panel as a project reminder rather than
a substitute for approval.
The reliable path is simple: prepare a minimal CSV, map
the columns, verify the imported sources and then code visibly.
Open the QualCanvas training centre for the next tutorial on
cases and cross-case comparison.