Cross-case analysis is useful when your question depends on comparison.
In QualCanvas, a case can represent a participant, site, organisation
or another unit that your method defines.
Decide that unit before building the comparison.
Open Tools and choose Cases.
Give each case a safe research label and a short
description that explains what it represents.
Avoid putting identifiable participant details into the display name.
Link the relevant transcripts or imported responses to each case.
Check the assignments carefully: a missing or duplicated source can
produce a convincing-looking comparison based on the wrong membership.
Choose Cross-Case from the Tools menu.
QualCanvas summarises how codes appear across the cases you created.
Treat the view as a route back to evidence, not
as an automatic conclusion.
For a structured case-by-question view, open Analyze and choose Framework Matrix.
The matrix supports systematic comparison while preserving the need to
inspect the original excerpts and contextual notes.
Write down why a difference may matter, what context could
explain it and which case does not fit the emerging
account.
A comparison becomes analytically useful when its reasoning is documented.
Define the unit, assign sources consistently, compare patterns, return to
the evidence and memo your reasoning.
Continue in the training centre with the QDPX transfer tutorial
when a project needs to move between tools.