QDPX is an open exchange format for qualitative projects.
QualCanvas can export and import QDPX, which helps when work
needs to move to or from a compatible tool.
Always plan time to verify the round trip.
Open the Export and import menu.
Use QDPX for project exchange, while reports, spreadsheets and images
serve different handoff needs.
Save the export in an approved research location.
For import, choose Import QDPX and select a QDPX or
ZIP package within the displayed twenty-megabyte limit.
Read the warning in the dialog before changing an existing canvas.
For the first transfer, work in a copy or fresh destination canvas.
That gives you a recoverable comparison if a source type,
code relation or formatting detail maps differently between applications.
After import, compare source counts, open sample excerpts and inspect
the codebook, hierarchy and memos.
Features that are unique to either application may not have
a one-to-one equivalent in the exchange format.
A QDPX package can contain participant text and analytical notes.
Encrypt or otherwise protect it where your protocol requires, send
it only to authorised recipients and delete temporary copies according
to your retention plan.
A responsible QDPX handoff includes a backup, a controlled transfer,
structured verification and a note of anything that changed.
The QualCanvas training centre includes separate tutorials for reports, spreadsheets
and visual exports.