A visual canvas becomes more valuable as the analysis grows,
but only if you can still find the relevant evidence.
QualCanvas includes layout and navigation controls that help without changing
your coding decisions.
Choose Fit View when nodes have moved beyond the visible area.
Start from the full structure, then zoom or pan toward
the source, code or memo you need instead of repeatedly
dragging the canvas at random.
Open More canvas actions and choose Auto-arrange layout when the
workspace needs a clean starting point.
Auto-arrange changes positions; it does not decide what your evidence
means or rewrite the analytical links you created.
Press Control K to open the command palette.
Search for a canvas action, run it and return to the analysis.
Keyboard shortcuts are especially useful during repeated coding and review sessions.
Open Sources when you need a stable route back to
an interview or response.
The visual layout should support the evidence trail, not replace
careful reading of the source material.
Switch between light and dark display modes for the working
environment that suits you.
On a phone, use the canvas for quick review; detailed
visual organisation is clearer on a larger screen.
Fit the view, arrange when useful, search for commands and
keep returning to the source.
Continue in the training centre with the repository tutorial for
organising insights across more than one project.