When research spans several projects, useful insights can disappear into separate files.
The QualCanvas Research Repository provides a place to curate insight
records across projects while the detailed analysis remains in each
canvas.
Open Research Repository from your authenticated workspace.
Repository access depends on the current QualCanvas plan, so confirm
availability before designing a team process around it.
Choose New Repository and add a name and description.
A durable customer journey, service area or research programme usually
makes a better boundary than a temporary presentation deadline.
Each canvas remains the home of transcripts, coding and project-level reasoning.
Promote a concise insight only after reviewing its supporting evidence,
context and limitations.
Before adding an insight, capture the claim, the evidence behind
it, the context in which it applies and any uncertainty
or negative cases.
A memorable sentence without those boundaries can become misleading when reused.
For a team repository, assign owners and review dates.
Retire or revise an insight when later research changes the
evidence, and maintain the same participant privacy controls used in
the source project.
A useful repository has a clear scope, traceable evidence, contextual
limits, named ownership and regular review.
Visit the QualCanvas training centre for applied-research workflows that connect
interviews, surveys and team handoffs.