UX, service and applied researchers often need to move quickly
without losing the chain of evidence.
QualCanvas brings source material, coding, patterns and research memos into
one visual workspace for review and handoff.
Define the decision, audience and method before opening the tool.
A discovery study, service evaluation and programme review may use
similar interviews, but they do not automatically support the same
claim.
Add interview transcripts, workshop notes or other approved text sources.
Use fictional or de-identified labels, and keep consent and data-handling
rules aligned with the environment where the research was collected.
For open-text survey material, import a clean CSV and map
the meaningful fields.
Do not bring in identifying columns merely because the survey
export included them.
Code excerpts, group related ideas and preserve links back to the source.
The visual structure helps a stakeholder see how a recommendation
developed, while the researcher remains responsible for context and rival
explanations.
Use a report for narrative review, a workbook for structured
checking, an image for explaining relationships or QDPX for compatible
project exchange.
Remove participant material that the recipient is not authorised to receive.
Frame the decision, collect only what you can govern, code
visibly, challenge the emerging account, memo the reasoning and hand
off the right level of evidence.
Follow the full QualCanvas training path for step-by-step practice.